Robert H. Taylor Collection of English and American Literature, 1280s-1958 (bulk 1800s-1930s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 3: Modern Manuscripts (Unbound) and Correspondence, 1545-1969; 23 archival boxes
  - Montgomery, Robert, 1807-1855, 1829; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to the Lord Bishop of Bath and Wells, 1829; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Moore, George, 1852-1933, 1916; 1 folder
    - 4 letters 1916 1 to "Miss Gough," 1 to Harper & Bros.; 1 to Mr. Werner Lauriel; 1 to Mr. Ellsworth, portion of 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous papers, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852, 1814-1825; 1 folder
    - 4 letters 1814-1825: 1 John Murray, 1 to "Mrs. LeFanu," 1 to unidentified person; 1 to Rt. Hon. John Wilson Croker, portion of 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - 1 manuscript circa 1825 preface to the 5th edition of his Life of Sheridan, consisting of a 3-page offprint from The Times with holograph corrections by Moore, 3 pp. of autograph manuscript, and 2 pp. of scribal manuscript with his holograph corrections, 8 pp. (total), portion of 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - More, Hannah, 1745-1833, 1809-1815; 1 folder
    - 13 letters 1809-1815 1 to Messrs. Cadell and Davies, 3 to Mr. J. Corkfield; 1 to Rev .Dr. Coulthurst; 2 to Mrs. Quincy c/o Rev. P. Searle, 1 to Thomas Raffles; 1 by Frances Reynolds; 4 letters to various recipients; and miscellaneous papers, 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Morier, James Justinian, 1780-1849, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to A. Westmacott, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Morison, Fynes, 1604; 1 folder
    - 1 document(?), 1604; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Murray, Alma, 1854-1945, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter (reply) to Bernard Shaw, undated (on verso of 1894 letter to Murray by Shaw); 1 signed photograph, undated, 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Murray, John, 1778-1843, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to unidentified person, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Newman, John Henry, 1801-1890, 1882; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Mr. Trollope" [Anthony Trollope], 1882; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Newton, Isaac, Sir, 1642-1727, 1693; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter to Samuel Pepys, 1693; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Newton, John, 1725-1807, 1783; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Rev. Bowman", 1783; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Nineteenth Century Poetry, undated; 1 folder
    - 8 manuscripts of verse (6 pp., 3 leaves, undated): "The Wife's Address to her Husband" by Mr. Lewis; "The Husband's Apology" by the same, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - "Hope and Grief" by Wm. M-?; "On the Two Barringtons", dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - "Without Her" (H of L); "The Lover's Walk", undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - "The Orchard-Pits"; "Spring-Tribute" (H of L), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - O'Shaughnessy, Arthur Wiliam Edgar, 1844-1881, 1879-1880; 1 folder
    - Two original manuscripts, 1879-1880; 1 folder
      - verse, "Nocturne", undated; 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - 5 letters to Pakenham Beatty, 1879-1880verse, "We are the music makers ...;"miscellaneous papers, portion of 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Oliphant, Mrs. (Margaret), 1828-1897, 1869-1884; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 36)
    Correspondents: JOHN BLACKWOOD (1869), ARTHUR GORDON (1883), ALEXANDER WILLIAM KINGLAKE (n.d.), ALEXANDER MACMILLAN (1874), JOHN MORLEY (1881), SIR HENRY FREDERICK PONSONBY (1881), BARON VON TAUCHNITZ (1884).
  - Ormonde, James Butler, Duke of, 1610-1688, 1670; 1 folder
    - Authorization for Poet Laureate Dryden's Wine, 1670; 1 folder
      - 1 document (warrant), directing that a butt or pipe of canary wine be delivered yearly to "John Driden Esqr" on his appointment as Poet Laureate, undated; 1 p. (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Patmore, Coventry, 1823-1896, 1860; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to J. W. Parker, 1860; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Peacock, Thomas Love, 1785-1866, 1857; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter to Mary Ellen [Meredith], 1857; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Pembroke, Mary Sidney, Countess of, 1561-1621, 1590-1599; 1 folder
    - 1 letter (signed by the Earl of Pembroke also) to the Earl of Essex [Robert Devereux], 1590s; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Pepys, Samuel, 1633-1703, 1667-1701; 3 folders
    - Autograph letters and document, 1667-1697; 1 folder
      - 2 letters 1672-1697: 1 to Sir Thomas Osborne, 1 to "Mrs. Shelcross;" 2 signatures by Pepys, 1667, portion of 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - 1 document 1678: "Instructions for our very good Lord & Lord Yarmouth Vice-Admiral of Norfolk touching & impressing of nine-hundred & fifty seamen..."(signed by others also), 3 pp. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Autograph letter to and by Jackson, 1700-1701; 1 folder
      - 2 letters 1700-1701: 1 to his nephew J. Jackson, 1 by J. Jackson, 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - MS. Account of Employment in.... Admiralty, 1678 March 2- 9; 1 folder
      - 1 manuscript undated "The encouragements his Majesty...," 2 pp., with 2 signed notes by James II and 1 signed note by Charles II, 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Percy, Algernon, Sir, 4th Duke of Northumberland, 1859 November 25; 1 folder
    - 1 menu: "Dinner for 600 Workman... at Alnwick Castle, ", 1859 November 25; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Percy, Thomas, 1729-1811, 1754-1801; 1 folder
    - 3 letters 1754-1801: 1 to Thomas Apperly, 1 to William Sotheby, 1 (in third person) to Cadell and Davis (with accompanying memorandum of agreement, 1797), 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Pilon, Frederick, 1750-1788, 1785; 1 folder
    - 1 manuscript: "Fair American. Act 3d.," with alterations in unknown hand, [32] leaves, in wrappers, not published until, 1785; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Piozzi, Hester Lynch Thrale, 1741-1821, 1782-1821; 3 folders
    - 3 letters 1782-1815 1 to "Major Barry," 1 (initialed fragment) to Fanny Burney, 1 to Thomas Sedgwick Whalley; and miscellaneous papers, 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Autograph letters, 1811-1821; 1 folder
      - 8 letters 1811-1821: 1 to Clement Francis (nephew), 1 to W. Kenrick, 1 to Mrs. [Penelope] Pennington, 3 to Miss Williams, 1 to Miss Willoughby, 1 small card, signed, 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - 1 letter to Mrs. [Penelope] Pennington, 1801; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Polidori, 1816; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Pryce Gordon, 1816; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - The Poor Whore's Petition, undated; 1 folder
    - Autograph manuscript, 1 p., undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744, 1711-1743; 5 folders
    - 2 letters: 1 to William Fortescue, undated; 1 to Charles Ford, undated, 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Autograph letter to [George] Arbuthnot, 1741; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Autograph letter to Mrs. Martha Blount, 1734; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Autograph letters, 1711-1743; 1 folder
      - 10 letters 1711-1743 1 to [George Berkeley], 2 to John Hughes, 2 to Mr. [Jonathan] Richardson, 1 to Mr. Pilkington, 1 to Dr. Oliver, 1 to Jacob Tonson, 1 to Sir William Trumbull, 1 letter by Charles Jarvis to [Sir William Trumbull], written on Pope's letter to Trumbull, 1 to unidentified person, 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - "Epitaph on John Ld. Caryl", 1711; 1 folder
      - 1 letter to John Caryll containing a verse epitaph for his uncle (of same name), 1711; portion of 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - manuscript of verse, 2 stanzas (17 lines), on letter to Caryll's nephew, 1711; portion of 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Porter, Endymion, 1587-1649, 1625-1630; 2 folders
    - Autograph letter, circa 1625; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Autograph letter to his wife, circa 1630; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Porter, Jane, 1776-1850, 1832; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Mr. Willis", 1832; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972, 1910; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Elkin Mathews, 1910; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Prior, Matthew, 1664-1721, 1709; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter to the Duke of Marlborough, 1709; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Procter, Anne Benson Skepper, 1887; 1 folder
    - Correspondence, 1887; 1 folder
      - 35 letters (1874-1887) to "Mr. Archdale" and/or "Mrs. Archdale," including a letter to and by Anne Ritchie (daughter of W. M. Thackeray) 1887 copied by Procter, 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Procter, Edythe Anna, undated; 1 folder
    - 4 letters (undated) to "Mr. Archdale", 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Radcliffe, Ann, 1764-1823, undated; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter, undated; 1 folder
      - 1 letter to "Miss Williamson," circa1800, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Raleigh, Walter, Sir, 1552?-1618, 1605-1618 October 28; 1 folder
    - The Lie (contemporary ms.), 1605-1618 October 28; 1 folder
      - manuscript of "A Speech from the Scaffold," given by Raleigh on the morning of his execution, 1618 October 28manuscript of verse, "The Lie," 15 stanzas beginning "Goe soule the bodyes guest...," in a contemporary hand, 2 pp., circa 1605, 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Récamier, Juliette, 1777-1849, 1819; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Maria Edgeworth, circa 1819; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792, 1778; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "My Lord", 1778; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Richardson, Samuel, 1689-1761, 1705-1768; 4 folders
    - 2 annuity documents (1747-1751) and 1 letter, possibly to his friend Hester Mulso, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Autograph letter to "dear Sir [Andrew Millar, Scottish bookseller, 1705-1768], dear Mrs. Millar, and Miss Johnson," 1750, 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Autograph letter to Rev. Dr. Samuel Lobb, 1755; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Letters to and from Samuel Richardson, 1753-1761; 1 folder
      - 11 letters 1753-1761: 1 to Miss Highmore, 2 by Miss E. Pennington, 2 to Miss Pennington, 1 by Frances Sheridan, 1 letter by William Warburton to "Mr. Leake" about Richardson's Sir Charles Grandison with 1 note by J. Leake in reply, on bottom of Warburton's letter to him, 1 to "Your Ladiship," 1 to unidentified person "my Lord," 1 to unidentified person, 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ritchie, Anne, 1837-1919, undated; 1 folder
    - Correspondence, undated; 1 folder
      - 10 to Mrs. Field, 1 to "To my dear Friends," 2 to unidentified persons. 1 (card) to Maggs Brothers, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Robinson, Mary, 1758-1800, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Mrs. Robinson, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Rogers, Samuel, 1763-1855, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to unidentified person, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Ross, Robert Baldwin, 1905; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Richard Butler Glaenzer, 1905; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Rossetti, Christina, 1830-1894, undated; 1 folder
    - 6 letters to various people, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882, undated; 1 folder
    - 3 letters to unidentified persons, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Rossetti, Lucy Maddox, undated; 1 folder
    - 3 letters to Professor Dowden, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Rossetti, William Michael, 1829-1919, undated; 2 folders
    - "Prefatory Notice", undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Autograph letters to Edward Dowden, 1870-1904, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Mr. Hewitt," 1 letter to "My dear Dullas", undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Sadleir, Michael, 1888-1957, undated; 2 folders
    - 2 letters to Vallance and Wilson, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Trollope's Orley Farm Artist Proofs, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Sayers, Dorothy L., 1893-1957, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Miss E-?, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Scott, Walter, Sir, 1771-1832, 1807-1831; 2 folders
    - Autograph manuscripts and letters, undated; 1 folder
      - 3 letters: 1 ALS (initialed) to William Erskine, Lord Kinneder, 1 ALS to "Mr. Musquirier[?]", 1 ALS to G. Gilchrist, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - 2 manuscripts: verse, "The Bonnets of Bonnie Dundee," AMs, 3 pp.; prose, one page of The Abbott, AMs, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Autograph letters, 1807-1831; 1 folder
      - 9 letters 1807-1831: 1 to Maria Edgeworth 1813, 1 to Robert Southey 1813, 7 to unidentified persons, 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Searle, Ronald, 1920, 1957; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Mr. Sim, 1957; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Severn, Joseph, 1793-1879, 1940; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "My dear Sir," circa 1940, and miscellaneous papers, 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Seward, Anna, 1747-1809, 1808; 1 folder
    - 3 letters: 1 to "My dear Madam;" 1 to Dr. Mansel(?); 1 to Mrs. Sterndale, 1808; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Shaw, George Bernard, 1856-1950, 1885-1949; more than 17 folders
    - Manuscripts, 1913; 1 folder
      - "[Taste]" (in Gregg shorthand), 1913 stanzas, 2 pp., dedicated to Mrs. Patrick Campbell, with typescript copy, portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - "Cock Robin" (in Gregg shorthand), 1913 9 stanzas, 1 p., dedicated to Mrs. Patrick Campbell, with typescript copy, portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - "Contribution to S.M.N.T. Album" (in Gregg shorthand), undated 7 pp., with notes for 7 illustrations, with typescript copy, portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1885-1930; portion of 1 folder
      - 7 letters 1885-1930: 2 to "Mrs. Beatty," 1 to Morley Dainow, 1 to [Frank Harris], 1 to Bradford Merrill, 1 to J. B. Pinker, 1 to unidentified person [PLUS 1 by Sidney Webb 1915-moved from Shaviana], portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - 97 letters (1912-1925) to Paul R. Reynolds: 51 letters, 21 cards, 24 telegrams, and 1 by Shaw's secretary, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Reynolds I, 1912; 3 letters (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Reynolds II, 1913; 9 letters (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Reynolds III, 1914; 13 letters (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Reynolds IV, 1915; 7 letters (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Reynolds V, 1916; 14 letters (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Reynolds VI, 1917; 20 letters (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Reynolds VII, 1918; 10 letters (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Reynolds VIII, 1919; 10 letters (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Reynolds IX, 1920-1925; 11 letters (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - George Bernard Shaw Autograph Letters, 1886-1949; 1 folder
      - 53 letters 1886-1949: 1 to Grant Allen, 7 to Dion Boucicault, 1 to Mrs. Dion Boucicault, 11 to Miss Alma Murray (also Mrs. A. M. Forman), 4 to Conal O'Riordan, 1 to Paul Selver, 4 to Clement King Shorter, 1 to H. S. Salt, 4 to Irene Vanbrugh, 1 to Hesketh Pearson, 1 to Dr. [Frederick] Furnivall (with a note by Furnivall in reply), 1 to Sir Winston Churchill titled at top "Memoranda for the Right Honorable Winston Churchill re article on Shaw," 3 to J. W. Robertson Scott, 1 to Rev. S. Anderson, 1 to Hester Bancroft, 1 to "Blandchamp"(?), 1 to H. J. B. Craven, 1 to "My dear Edy"(?), 1 to Miss Amy Lawrence, 1 to Miss Millie Murby, 1 to Karel Musek, 1 to [Sidney Olivier], 1 to Chas. Overton, 1 to Katharine Pole, 1 to H. Greenbaugh Smith, 1 card to unidentified person, portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - 4 letters (1916-1939) to Shaw with notes by Shaw in reply: 1 letter by Jonathan Cape, 1 by Rita Devoti, 1 by Charles Hemstreet, 1 by J. W. Robertson Scott, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - photograph, inscribed to Israel Cohen, 1949; portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - watercolor, stage design for John Bull's Other Island (Act IV, Scene 1), 7" x 10", undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Letters of George Bernard Shaw, 1888-1929; 1 folder
      - 34 letters 1888-1929: 1 note (on June Hope's manuscript), 1 to John Lane, 1 to S. Stepniak, 1 to Edward Gordon Craig, 1 to Perriton Maxwell, 1 note (on letter by Jem Nicholls to the Editor of the Star), 1 to Ellis Roberts, 2 to "Miss Broadley," 1 to Stanley W. Bull (at bottom of Bull's letter to Shaw), 1 to Stanley Parker (at bottom of Parker's letter to Shaw), 1 to J. W. Cragg(?), 1 to Felix Moscheles, 3 to Basil Martin, 1 to "Spence," 1 to J. Cuthbert Hadden, 1 to "My dear Edie," 1 to F. B.(?) Robinson, 1 to "Mr. Lunn," 1 to Philip Frankford, 1 to Arthur Woolerston, 1 to Clarence Rook, 1 to Gerald Cumberland, 1 to "Mr. Symonds," 1 to "Mr. Overton," 1 to Arthur S. Clark, 1 to Jean S. Spence, 1 about Ellen Terry to an unidentified person, 2 to unidentified persons, 2 cards to unidentified persons, portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - 2 letters to 1926-1928: 1 by Stanley W. Bull (with reply by Shaw), 1 by A. Stanley Parker (with reply by Shaw), portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Shaviana I-IX: 9 folders 1915-1929: Contains correspondence of Paul R. Reynolds, Shaw's American agent, with various people about Shaw (approx. 60 letters), several letters (copies) by Shaw, and a 1-page typed manuscript by Shaw entitled "The Moral of Samuel Butler's Career.", 9 folders (Box 15, Folder 22-30)
    - The Elizabethan Sketch, 1910; 1 folder
      - prose, "The Elizabethan Sketch" [Dark Lady of Sonnets] (in Gregg shorthand), 11 pp., 1910; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Love Among the Artists, dates not examined; 1 folder
      - prose, "Love Among the Artists" (fragment), 6 pp., numbered (292)-(297), undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - The Old Revolutionist and the New Revolution, undated; 1 folder
      - prose, "The Old Revolutionist and the New Revolution", undated; 16 pp. (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Shelley, Mary Wollstonecraft, 1797-1851, 1817-1838; 2 folders
    - Correspondence, 1817-1824; 1 folder
      - 5 letters 1817-1824: 1 to Charlotte Figge, 1 to Leigh Hunt, 1 to Charles Ollier, 1 to Percy Bysshe Shelley, 1 to Edward John Trelawny; miscellaneous papers, 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Manuscripts, 1833-1838; 1 folder
      - prose, "Angelina," (incomplete), 1833 34 pp., published as "The Brother and Sister, an Italian Story", portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 35)
      - verse, "O listen while I sing to thee...," 1838 two 4-line stanzas, a leaf from an album, portion of 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822, 1810-1859 March; 2 folders
    - Manuscript about Shelley, 1816-1859 March; 1 folder
      - prose, biographical sketch of Shelley (in unknown hand), 3 pp., undated; rosebud from Shelley's grave, Rome, 1859 spring; note signed by Shelley, 1816; miscellaneous papers, 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Autograph letters, 1810-1815; 1 folder
      - 3 letters 1810-1815 1 to Edward Graham, 2 to unidentified people; 1 check, "Pay to Mr. Clairmont or bearer five pounds", 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Shenstone, William, 1714-1763, 1753-1772 August 21; 1 folder
    - 2 letters 1753-1756: 1 to Richard Graves, 1 to George Lyttleton, 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - AMS of the epitaph of William Shenstone by Richard Graves in letter to Mrs. Wigans, at John Hodgets’ house, Snow Hill, Birmingham, Claverton, 1772 August 21; AM 2016-8; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Sheridan, Charles Brinsley, 1816; 1 folder
    - 2 letter fragments, including 1 to "My dear Brother", 1816; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1751-1816, 1772-1949; portions of 2 boxes
    - I. Letters (36 letters (1782-[1816]) in 3 folders), 1793-1809; 3 folders
      - I.1 (15 letters and 1 document): 2 to "My Dear Tom" [Sheridan] by his father, Richard Brinsley Sheridan, 1 letter to Thomas Sheridan by James Toakley(?) containing a note initialed by R. B. Sheridan, 1 letter to Messrs. Jenkins & James, 6 letters to unidentified persons, 2 letter(?) drafts (incomplete), 3 about Theatre Royal Drury Lane "Copy Prayer of a Petition intended to be presented by the New Renters of the Theatre Royal Drury Lane to the Lord Chancellor" (unsigned), 1 leaf, 3 pages, circa 1793-1802; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - I.2 (11 letters): 1 to {Mr. Burgess] 1809 1 to [Charles James] Fox, 1 to L. Holland, 4 to [William] Keen (1 with an additional note by Rob Fairbrother), 3 to Mr. Peake(?), 1 to Lady Caroline Lamb, 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - I.3 (11 letters): 2 to Mr. Saintbury(?), 1 bet (signed by Sheridan and witnessed by H. C. Combe), 1 to William Capon 1806, 1 (printed) to The Rev'd Doctor [Samuel] Parr, 2 to unidentified persons, 1 to Charles Ward, 1 to Sir Richard Ford, 1 from Sheridan's deathbed to [Matthew Cotes Wyatt], undated; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - II. Related Corres. - Notebooks, undated; 1 folder
      - 8 letters (1807-1817) about Sheridan: 2 by Edward Chandler to Robert Fairbrother, 1 by Fairbrother to Chandler, 1 by George Edwards to [Mr.] Cocker, 2 by Robert Fairbrother to William Keen, 1 by William Keen to Charles B. Sheridan, and 1 by James Heath to [C. W. Ward], dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - 1 notebook of memoranda of cash paid and received at Polsden (1815-1816) for R. B. Sheridan by Robert Fairbrother, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - 1 notebook of notes (1815-1816) by Robert Fairbrother on tenant farmers renting land owned by R. B. Sheridan, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - III. Notebooks, 1772-1816; more than 2 folders
      - 1 notebook of miscellaneous notes including "repairs noted on Somerset Place House", 1807; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - IV. Financial (4 folders), undated; 1 item
        - 35 receipts and bills for goods and services, bonds, indentures, 1772-1816; 4 folders (Box 16, Folder 7-10)
    - V.1 Marriage Docs, 1811 July 29; 1 folder
      - "Agreement between the Right Honorable Richard B. Sheridan and Mrs. Sheridan....of their marriage articles", 1811 July 29; 15 pp. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - V.2 Marriage Docs, 1795 April 25-1815 August 16; 1 folder
      - "Minute of the transactions between Mr. Sheridan and his trustees," marriage settlement, 1795 April 25 to 1815 August 16, 5 pp. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - V.3 Marriage Docs, 1795 April 24-1816; 1 folder
      - "Statement under the trusts of Mr. and Mrs. Sheridan's marriage settlement," 1795 April 24 to 1816, 35 pp. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - VI. Patent, 1808; 1 folder
      - Letter patent of George, Prince of Wales, appointing Sheridan as Receiver General of the Duchy of Cornwall, 1808; 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - VII.1 Manuscripts, undated; 1 folder
      - an alphabetical acrostic beginning "A. was an awning which covered the Queen...", undated; 1 p. (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - notebook containing "An Epistle From a Coliflower To Christopher Anstey Esq." with "Apology to Mr. Artichoke," watermarked 1776, in paperbound notebook, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - "I never felt myself so little inclined to apologise...," speech given in Parliament, undated; 4 pp. (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - VII.2 Manuscripts, 1778-1780; 1 folder
      - fragment of an unfinished drama, "I rage and storm...", undated; 1 p. (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - "On Absentees" (incomplete prose draft), circa 1778; 19 pp. (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - "...to the hopes of anxious industry..." (fragment), from "Pizarro", circa 1780; 2 pp. (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - "Peruvian woman..." (fragment), from "Pizarro," Act III, Scene I, undated; 1 p. (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - "Pray how did she look...," humorous verses on Lady Ann Hamilton, undated; 1 p. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - VII.3 Manuscripts, 1801; 1 folder